# **NADUN DE SILVA**

#### **Lead Software Engineer**

Auckland, New Zealand
https://linkedin.com/in/nadundesilva

https://nadundesilva.comhttps://github.com/nadundesilva

# Summary

Lead Software Engineer with 7 years of experience in cloud-native application development in Kubernetes and other cloud platforms. Background in architecture, user experience (UX), development, and deployment of cloud-native applications in production environments. Experience in owning the technical direction of product areas and leading a team of engineers.

# **Experience**

#### Senior Software Engineer

**Orion Health** 

Movember 2022 to Present

• Auckland, New Zealand

- Directed the successful deployment of Indexity using AWS infrastructure; conducted thorough disaster recovery planning, which reduced potential downtime risks from unforeseen incidents by at least 40%.
- Championed an end-to-end deployment strategy for Indexity within an SRE framework on GitLab and AWS, resulting in a faster rollout time that decreased development cycles by one day per development cycle.
- Orchestrated comprehensive threat modeling and privacy assessments, leading to stronger safeguards, resulting in no major vulnerabilities detected by penetration tests initiated by customers.
- Enhanced the precision of phone number searches by implementing Apache Lucene-based indexing techniques, improving the patient searches across two customers.
- Developed the Terraform code for deploying self-hosted GitLab runners on Google Cloud, reducing the development costs by more than 50%.

#### Associate Technical Lead

WSO2

Ocolombo, Sri Lanka

- Secured the Sustained Outstanding Contribution Award thrice in a row, an honor given exclusively to only the top 5% of all company staff members who demonstrated exceptional technical leadership and innovative contributions throughout tenure.
- Led a senior software engineer in developing the minimum viable features for the resource scheduling of the Choreo online editor within 1.5 months, using Kubernetes and GoLang.
- Eliminated bottlenecks, reducing the startup time of the Kubernetes resources of the Choreo Editors by 80% and increasing the overall user experience.
- Reduced the MsSQL database utilization by 60% by introducing a Redis cache and randomization of cache expiry times, increasing the number of users the system can handle.
- Led the product team, completing 95% of the team targets and sprint milestones on time by prioritizing tasks and fostering a good working environment.

#### Senior Software Engineer

WSO<sub>2</sub>

**ii** July 2019 to June 2021

Oclombo, Sri Lanka

- Spearheaded the implementation of the foundation for Choreo observability within 3 months with a team of 2 other engineers, creating the backbone of Choreo observability.
- Decreased the cost by 90% for the company by architecting the Choreo observability storages, including data archival into a Data Lake for Machine Learning (ML) use cases.
- Improved debugging experience for users by revamping the observability instrumentation at the Ballerina compiler level within 1 month to map the observability data to the source code.
- Minimized the number of bugs in the Choreo Observability area by implementing proper code reviewing, testing, and deployment practices in a team of 6 engineers.

### Software Engineer

WSO2

- **January 2018 to July 2019**
- Ocolombo, Sri Lanka
- Delivered the Cellery observability basic features within 2 months for observing microservice composites using Kubernetes, Istio, OpenTracing, and Envoy.
- Headed the implementation of Cellery developer tools using VSCode Language Server Extensions and visualizations of Cells using D3.
- Developed Cellery Hub backed by a Docker Registry as the storage and implemented the authentication of the CLI and portal using OpenID Connect (OIDC) within 1 month.
- Implemented the observability aspects of the WSO2 Serverless Platform using Prometheus and Jaeger on top of Kubernetes and OpenWhisk.

#### **Skills**

- Programming languages Java, GoLang, Scala, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Cloud Platforms AWS, GCP, Azure
- Frameworks and tools Terraform, Kubernetes Operator Framework, React, Ansible, ExpressJS
- Storages Time-series Databases (Influx DB, Azure Data Explorer), Graph Databases (Orient DB), Data Lakes (Azure Data Lake), Relational Databases (MySQL, MsSQL), Redis
- Containerization Kubernetes, Azure Kubernetes Service, AWS ECS, Docker, Kustomize, Helm
- CI/CD Tools and Practices GitOps, GitHub Actions, GitLab
- Observability Tools and Platforms OpenTelemetry, DataDog, Prometheus, Jaeger, CloudWatch
- API Protocols REST, GraphQL, gRPC
- Software Development Methodologies Agile, DevOps

#### **Education**

## B.Sc. (Hons.) in Engineering (Computer Science and Engineering)

**University of Moratuwa** 

Colombo, Sri Lanka

- Attained a GPA of 3.85 out of 4.20, obtaining a First Class.
- Placements in Dean's List in 6 out of 8 semesters at the University of Moratuwa.
- Awarded Global Finalist (Galactic Impact) in the NASA Space Apps Challenge 2017.
- Completed Google Summer of Code 2017.

## Certifications

Certified Kubernetes Administrator

The Linux Foundation 

December 2020

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer

The Linux Foundation 

iii January 2020

Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning

Build Basic Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs)

Deep Learning Specialization

### **Publications**

- "Generative Adversarial Networks (GAN) based Anomaly Detection in Industrial Software Systems" published in 2019 at the Moratuwa Engineering Research Conference (MERCon)
- "Anomaly Detection in Industrial Software Systems Using Variational Autoencoders" published in 2017 at the Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Pattern Recognition Applications and Methods (ICPRAM)